Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/riogunturutomo (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Information Assurance

Qualitative & Quantitative Research Methodologies

Information Security

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Indonesian (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

Master Scholarship

Doctoral Scholarship

Publications

MOOCs as an alternative to distance learning model for University in Indonesia

Factors affecting the implementation of information assurance for eGovernment in Indonesia

Towards Confirming an Information Assurance Framework for eGovernment in Indonesia

Analyzes of cybercrime expansion in Indonesia and preventive actions

Rio Guntur Utomo

Researcher - Information Assurance - University of Southampton Southampton, United Kingdom

Summary

A self-motivated and passionate fellow in information assurance field. I obtained my Bachelor of Engineering (BE) in Informatics Engineering from the Universitas Islam Negeri Sunan Gunung Djati Bandung in 2012. I also obtained the Master of Science (MS) in Informatics from the Institut Teknologi Bandung in 2015. I am currently pursuing my PhD degree in the University of Southampton as a part of Cyber Physical Systems Research Group. My thesis topic revolves around information assurance for e-government.

My research interests include information assurance, information security, e-government, smart cities, and e-learning.

Experience

University of Southampton
Researcher PHD Student
September 2016 - Present (3 years 6 months)
Southampton, United Kingdom

Research Topic: Information Assurance Framework for E-Government in Indonesia.

Universitas Islam Negeri Sunan Gunung Djati Bandung Lecturer

August 2015 - July 2016 (1 year)

Bandung Area, West Java, Indonesia

I served as a lecturer in Department of Informatics Engineering, Faculty of Science and Technology, for following lectures/modules:

Multimedia System.

Cryptography.

Sekolah Tinggi Teknologi Bandung Lecturer March 2015 - July 2015 (5 months) Bandung Area, West Java, Indonesia

I served as a lecturer in Department of Informatics Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, for following lectures/modules:

Database Management System.

Universitas Islam Negeri Sunan Gunung Djati Bandung Assistant Lecturer

January 2013 - July 2013 (7 months)

Bandung Area, West Java, Indonesia

I served as an assistant lecturer in Department of Informatics Engineering, Faculty of Science and Technology, for following lectures/modules:

Cryptography.

Dinas Komunikasi dan Informatika Internship June 2011 - July 2011 (2 months) Bandung Area, West Java, Indonesia

I developed an archive management web-based application for the organisation.

Education

University of Southampton

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Computer Science · (2016 - 2020)

Institut Teknologi Bandung

Master of Science - MS, Informatics · (2013 - 2015)

Universitas Islam Negeri Sunan Gunung Djati Bandung Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Informatics Engineering · (2008 - 2012)